Guide to the Southcomb Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Southcomb family papers
1696-1877
1818-1852
OSB MSS 156
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.71
(7 boxes)
The Southcomb Family Papers document some aspects of the clerical careers of several generations of members of the Southcomb family, which held the rectorship of Rose Ash in Devon for over 200 years. Included are devotional commonplace books of Lewis Southcomb; 279 sermons, mostly dating from the first half of the nineteenth century, by four different family members; and the diaries of John Ladeveze Hamilton Southcomb.
Southcomb family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Sotheby's on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Fund, 1979.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Printed works that were acquired with the Southcomb Family Papers were removed and cataloged separately. They are listed in the Appendix to this finding aid. Full catalog records for these items may be found in ORBIS, the Yale University Library catalog.
Southcomb Family of Rose Ash
Members of the Southcomb family served as rectors of the parish of Rose Ash in Devon almost uninterruptedly from 1675 until 1948. Only those represented in the Southcomb Family Papers are described here.
Lewis Southcomb (1655-1733), the first Southcomb to hold Rose Ash, refused to take the Oath of Allegiance to William and Mary in 1688, despite offers of preferment, and was deprived of the rectorship as a Nonjuror, but was restored after the death of James II in 1701. He was a noted preacher, and at least two of his sermons were printed in London during his lifetime.
John Southcomb (1758-1822), received his B.A. from Exeter College, Oxford in 1780 and married Susannah Granger in the same year. He succeeded his father John as rector of Rose Ash in 1788, also serving as patron of King's Nympton, and died in 1822.
John Southcomb (1784-1840), was the eldest son of John Southcomb and Susannah Granger. He received his B.A. in 1813 from Exeter College, Oxford and married Sarah Hamilton, the daughter of the Rev. William Hamilton of Donegal in 1817. Never rector of Rose Ash, to which his younger brother Edmund Hamilton (1792-1854) was preferred in 1822, John served as curate of Minehead and of St. Wenn in Cornwall until his death in 1840. John's son, John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb (1817-1886), received his B.A. from All Souls' College, Oxford in 1840 and succeeded to the rectorship of Rose Ash on the death of his childless uncle Edmund in 1854.
Scope and Contents
The Southcomb Family Papers document some aspects of the clerical careers of several generations of members of the Southcomb family who successively held the rectorship of Rose Ash in Devon. Contents include three devotional commonplace books of Lewis Southcomb; 279 sermons, mostly dating from the first half of the nineteenth century, by four different family members; and the diaries of John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb. The materials assembled here span almost 200 years of the family's 273 years in Rose Ash, but the bulk of the papers are the 279 manuscript sermons for worship services, funerals, farewells, charities, and other special occasions ("for the Princess Charlotte Saxe-Coburg buried November 1817"; "for the distressed Irish," June 26, 1831) written by John Southcomb (1758-1822), John Southcomb (1789-1840), Edmund Southcomb (1792-1854), John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb (1817-1886) and several as yet unidentified writers. The remainder of the collection consists of eight diaries by John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Commonplace Books of Lewis Southcomb, 1696-1731; II. Sermons, 1788-1872; III. Diaries of John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb, 1835-1877.
Appendix: List of Printed Works
Also among the Southcomb Papers were the following printed works:
-- 8 copies of J.L.H. Southcomb's Sermon "Liturgical Changes. Are they needful? Are they desirable?" preached 7 Jun 1860 at South Molton
-- 1 copy of "The Cathedral" A Sermon preached in the Cathedral Church of S. Peter Exeter on Sunday 7th January 1872 by Frederick Bishop of the Diocese
-- 3 printed almanacs: 1702 (in Welsh), 1744 and 1747
The five following published works, also part of the Southcomb Family Papers, are catalogued separately in the main card catalogue under the author's name:
-- Southcomb, Lewis (I), 1653-1733 "A Sermon Preached at the Funeral of the Reverend Mr. John Culme, Vicar of Ionaustone and Mollard, in Devon. December 2, 1691" London: 1692
19.5 cm x 15.5 cm, 32 p.
-- Southcomb, Lewis (II), 1684-1754
"The Great Christian Rule of Charity and Justice: Briefly considered in a Sermon."
Oxon: 1714
18 x 10.5 cm, 18 p.
-- Southcomb, Lewis (II), 1684-1754
"A Treatise Against the Converting of Tithes and Offerings to Secular uses."
Oxon: 1726
18 x 12 cm, 100 p.
-- Southcomb, Lewis (II), 1684-1754
"Subjection to the Higher Powers. A Necessary Duty in Every Christian. A Sermon"
London: 1735
19.5 x 12.5 cm, 31 p.
-- Southcomb, Lewis (II), 1684-1754
"The Christians Peculiar Character: Or Universal Love. The Truest Mark of a Christian"
Sherbourne: 1752
20 x 16 cm, 24 p.
Clergy -- England; Devotional literature, English; English poetry -- 18th century; Occasional sermons; Sermons, English -- 19th century; Devon (England); Great Britain -- Religion -- 19th century; Commonplace books; Sermons; Clergy; Southcomb, Edmund, 1792-1854; Southcomb, John, 1758-1822; Southcomb, John, 1784-1840; Southcomb, John Ladaveze Hamilton, 1817-1886; Southcomb, Lewis, 1653-; Southcomb family; Church of England -- Clergy -- Sermons; Church of England ( Clergy)
- Commonplace Books of Lewis Southcomb, (1653-1733), 1696-1731; Series I; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains three quarto sized bound commonplace books belonging to Lewis Southcomb (1653-1733). He used these notebooks for translations, poems, epigrams, prayers, notes for sermons and other assorted writings. Although his writings are mostly devotional, they do occasionally exhibit political sentiments.
  - "Poemata (qualiaqualia sunt), Epitaphia, Orationes, Epistolae...Versiones. Chronogrammata, etc.". in English, Greek, Latin and Hebrew containing poems, hymns and other notes, inscribed "Ludovico Tertio Sacerdote..." on title page. Items dated between 1696 and 1731 including: (Box 1, Folder 1)
    "Wickedness Reproved, or: A Satyr Against Villainy"
    "On a Bible Left behind by a Lady, and Sent to her by the Author"
    "Sumu ______ An Address to her Royale Highness Qu Ann. 1702"
    "On the Reformation-Book"
    "Cupid Baffled: A Love Song" Nov 5, 1707
    "Great Britain's Distress and Remedy" Nov 18, 1730
    "Qn Ann's Speech to the Parliament Apr 5, 1710"
  - "Poetical Aspirations: Or Divine Breathings Part 2nd" a manuscript volume of devotional poems including: (Box 2, Folder 2)
    "Maundy Thursday Apr. 15, 1731."
    "Religious Wisdom"
    "Seraphic Suit for Grace"
    "Divine Life Perfected"
    "Celestial Ejaculation"
  - Notes on St. Augustine, prayers and notes for sermons, signed and dated on the first page: 6 July 1696. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Greek, Latin & English.
    Excerpts from Bishop Lauds' Devotions
    "Mr. Selden's Recantation"
    A copy of a letter written to Mr. Kirkham Aug 15, 1715
    "Out of Parson's Christian Directory by Dr. Stanehope"
    Also Notes by John (III) Southcomb 1789-1840.
    From Pretymans Christian Theology
    Also annotations by John Landeveze Hamilton Southcomb, 1817-1886.
- Sermons, 1788-1872; Series II; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Sermons is organized into five subseries by author: John Southcomb (1758-1822); John Southcomb (1784-1840); Edmund Southcomb (1792-1854); Anonymous and Unattributed; and John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb (1817-1886).
  The series contains 279 sermons by four members of the Southcomb family. Most of the sermons contain notes as to when and where they were preached (some up to eight or ten times and by two or three different preachers), the amount collected in offertory, and their duration. Although John Southcomb was never rector at Rose Ash, his 137 sermons make up nearly half of the entire collection. Both his and Edmund's sermons are mostly devotional, and mostly unsigned.
  Because 95 per cent of the sermons assembled here are unsigned and only dated on the occasions preached, the handwriting and the first date and place of delivery for each sermon have been used as criteria for authorship. Where no date was inscribed on the sermon, the water mark date of the paper has been placed in square brackets; when there was no date and no water mark visible, the sermon has been placed at the end of the series.
  There are a few sermons, particularly among John Southcomb's (1784-1840), which have a strikingly different authorship; however, lacking better evidence, these have been attributed to him because the date and location noted on the sermon, and even the handwriting of the note itself, are consistent with others of his.
  Judging from the notes on the sermons, John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb, in addition to writing more than eighty sermons of his own, used and amended a great many of the sermons in this collection. Some of his sermons too reflect the important events of the times: included among his are a sermon "For the distressed Manufacturers -- Owing to the scarcity of cotton from the Yankee Civil War" and another "Written on occasion of Fast in consequence of the military outbreak in India," October 7, 1857.
  - John Southcomb ( 1758-1822)
    - Miscellaneous photocopies pertaining to Southcomb family and to Rose Ash. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1. 5 Oct 1788, Matt. 25:19 2. 8 May 1791, Luke 10:37 3. 24 Jul 1791 4. Dec 1794, Gen. 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 5. 5 May 1805, Matt. 16:26 6. 2 Aug 1807, Matt. 24:2 7. 23 Oct 1808, Tit. 2:8 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 8. 1816, Job 19:21, "South Molton Charity Sermon" 9. 30 Jul 1820, Heb. 11:13 10. 7 Jul 1822, Matt. 25:34-36 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - John Southcomb (1784-1840)
    - 11. 8 May 1814, Luke 16:26 12. [1815] or later, Mal. 2:10, "Sermon on the Trinity" 13. 31 Dec 1815, John 12:48 14. 28 Sep 1817, Matt. 28:6 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 16. 8 Feb 1818, 1 Chron. 28:9 17 & 18. 15 Feb 1818, Matt 15:28, For the Second Sunday in Lent; 22 Feb 1818, Eph. 5:9, For the Third Sunday in Lent 19 & 20. 22 Feb 1818, Eccl. 12:1 On the duties of the Young; 1 Mar 1818, Prov. 16:31 The duties of the Old 21. 26 Apr 1818, Rev 20:12-13 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 22. 3 May 1818, 1 Pet. 4:7, For the Sunday of the Ascension 23. 17 May 1818, 1 Cor. 15:33 24. 26 Jul 1818, Luke 19:41-44, For the tenth Sunday after Trinity. 25, 26 & 27. 2 Aug 1818, Luke 18:9, For the 11th Sunday after Trinity; 9 Aug 1818, 2 Cor 3:6, For the 12th Sunday after Trinity; 16 Sun 1818, Luke 19:37, For the 13th Sunday after Trinity 28. 25 Oct 1818, Psalm 119:94, The Xian's Surrender of himself to God (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 29. [1818] or later, Eccl. 8:11, God's delay of the Punishment of Sin 30. 14 Feb 1819, Luke 8:15, For Sexagesima Sunday 31. 15 Aug 1819, Matt 20:1, For Septuagesima Sunday 32. 25 Oct 1819, Luke 16:8, On the Parable of the unjust Steward (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 33. 26 Dec 1819, 1 Tim. 1:19, Farewell Sermon for Carhampton 34. 1 Apr 1820, Luke 15:20, The Sincere Penitent pitied and Forgiven 35. 14 May 1820, Acts 1:11 36. 23 Jul 1820, Luke 10:42, The one thing needful (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 37. 29 Apr 1821, Luke 23:28, Our Saviour's Solemn and Affectionate Warning 38. 10 Junn 1821, John 16:7-8, For Whitsunday 39. 30 Sep 1821, Matt 3:2, Repentance and Conversion 40. 23 Dec 1821, John 6:67-8, On the necessity of settled principles in Religion (fragment). 41. [1821] or later, 2 Tim. 1:10, Proofs of Immortality from Revelation 42. 30 Jun 1822, John 7:37 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 43. 11 Aug 1822, Lev. 19:12 44 & 45. 7 Sept 1823 (am), Joh 5:4); 7 Sept 1823 (pm) Isa 55:6 46. 2 Nov 1823 (am), Psalm 31:6 47. 2 Nov 1823 (pm), Isa. 61:1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 48. 9 Feb 1824, Rev. 3:5, The Rewards of the Conquering Christian 49. [1824] or later, John 11:25-6, A Funeral Discourse 50. [1824] or later, Matt 5:7, For the Benefit of the Widdescombe Infirmary. With 8pp. excerpted from a book of sermons, c. 1794. 51. 17 Jul 1825, Mark 8:1, Seventh Sunday after Trinity (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 52. 28 Aug 1825, Heb. 4:14-16. On Confirmation 53. 26 Oct 1825, For a Collection for rebuilding & increasing our Established Churches 54. 15 Jan 1826, Psalm 119:60, The Folly and Danger of Delaying 55. 4 Jun 1827, Matt 13:31, Fifth Sunday after the Epiphany 56. 8 Jul 1827, John 5:28-9, The General Resurrection. 57. 25 Dec 1828, John 1:14 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 58. 22 Feb 1829, Rev. 21:3-5, The happiness of heaven 59. 1 Mar 1829, John 3:5-6, For the fifth Sunday after the Epiphany 60. 1 Mar 1829, John 3:5-6, For the Sixth Sunday after after the Epiphany 61. 8 Mar 1829, Matt 4:1, For the First Sunday in Lent 62. 8 Mar 1829, Matt 20:6, For Septuagesima Sunday 63. 15 Mar 1829, Isa. 1:16-7 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 64. 26 Apr 1829, 1 John 5:4, For the First Sunday after Easter 65. 21 Jun 1829, Luke 16:31, First Sunday after Trinity 66. 12 Jul 1829, Sam 12:7, Fourth Sunday after Trinity 67. 19 Jul 1829, Rom 12:2 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 68. 20 Sep 1829, Matt. 18:14, Preached at South Molton for the benefit of the Charity Children, with later insert by J.L.H. Southcomb, 8 p. 69. 27 Dec 1829, John 1:11, Sunday after Christmas 1829 70. 3 Jan 1830, Psalm 39:6, New Year 71. 10 Jan 1830, Matt 8:10 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 72. 23 May 1830, Heb. 9:24, The Ascension of Christ to the Divine Presence on Our Behalf 73. 16 Jan 1831, Heb. 4:15, The Comparison of the High Priest of the Church 74. 1 May 1831, Rom. 5:1, Justification by Faith 75. 19 Jun 1831, John 7:45-46 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 76. 26 Jun 1831, Job 4:8-9, Preached for the distressed Irish 77. 24 July 1831, Psalm 90:12, Sunday after the Funeral for Mr. Pearce of Brolton Court 78. 6 Nov 1831, Psalm 84:2, The Desire of the faithful to enter the Courts of the Lord. 79. 13 Nov 1831, Matt. 11:28, On the Comforts of Religion (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 80. [1831] or later, Matt. 11:28 81. 29 Jan 1832, 2 Tim. 3:5 82. 26 Feb 1832 (am), Prov. 1:7 83. 26 Feb 1832 (pm), Luke 16:22-23 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 84. 18 Mar 1832, Luke 16:27-31 85. 21 Mar 1832, 1 Kings 8:37-40, Fast day for Cholera 86. 15 Apr 1832, John 8:46, The happiness of a virtuous life 87. 29 May 1832, 2 Cor. 13:11 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 88. 3 Jun 1832, Psalm 144:3 89. 16 Sep 1832, 1 Tim. 1:15 90. 20 Jan 1833, Gen. 6:3 91. 23 Sep 1832 (am), Num. 9: 9-10, 13 92. 23 Sep 1832 (pm), 1 Cor. 11:23-26 For the Sacrament 93. 30 Sep 1832, Acts 20: 25 & 32, Farewell Sermon at Minehead 94. 30 Sep 1832, Acts 20: 25 & 32, Farewell Sermon at Minehead 95. 4 Dec 1832, Acts 24: 16, A Conscience void of Offense 96. 11 Aug 1833, Rom. 14: 7-8, The Believing Union with Christ 97. 17 Nov 1833, Num. 23:10, The death of the Righteous 98. 1 Dec 1833, Heb. 9:27, Death and Judgement 99. 20 Apr 1834, Jam. 3:2, The Corruption of the human heart (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - 100 & 101. 7 Sep 1834, 2 Cor. 13:11, Farewell Sermon; No date, Psalm 72:8-11, For the Promotion of Christian Knowledge 102. [1835] or later, Luke 18:14, The Pharisee and the Publican 103. 30 May 1836, Luke 18:38, Miracle of the Blind Beggar 104. 17 Jul 1836, Matt. 25:14 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 105. 4 Sep 1836, 1 Kings 6:7, The building of the heavenly Temple 106. 9 Oct 1836 (am), Exo. 33:18, The Prayer of Moses for a view of God 107. 9 Oct 1836 (pm), Luke 7:12, The Funeral at the Gate of Nain 108. 6 Nov 1836. Isa. 43:25 [Fragment] 109. 6 Nov 1836. Acts 27:23-24, The Message Sent to Paul in the Storm (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 110. 13 Nov 1836, Psalm 113:5&6, The Condescension of God 111. [1836] or later, John 15:5, The True Vine 112. [1836] or later, 2 Sam. 12:13, The Afflicted David--A Pardoned Sinner 113. [N.D.], 2 Sam. 12:13, The Afflicted David--A Pardoned Sinner (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 114. Mar 1837, Luke 6:47-49, The Two Builders 115 & 116. 30 Apr 1837, Mark 10:26-27, The Disciples Wondering at the difficulties of Salvation; 21 May 1837, Matt. 11:28, Rest in Christ for the Heavy Laden 117. 18 Jun 1837, Luke 18:13, A Sinner Praying for Mercy 118. 9 Jul 1837, Psalm 23:1, David's Confidence in the Prospects of the Future. 119. 23 Jul 1837, 2 Tim. 1:18, St. Paul's Prayer for Onesiphorus (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - 120. 30 Jul 1837, 1 Sam. 4:13, Eli trembling before the Ark 121. 13 Aug 1837, Phil. 4:19, Man's need supplied from God's riches 122. 4 Dec 1838, Mal. 4:2, The Sun of Righteousness 123. 10 Dec 1838, Tit. 3:5, Our Life (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - 124. 13 Dec 1838, John 1:29, The Lamb of God (Atonement) 125. 13 Dec 1838, 1 Cor. 5:7-8, Christ our Passover (Easter) 126. 13 Dec 1838, 1 Cor. 3:11, Jesus Christ the Foundation 127. 15 Dec 1838, John 15:5, The True and Living Way (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 128. 18 Dec 1838, John 20:31, The Son of God 129. 23 Dec 1838, Matt. 5:17, The Fulfilling of the Law and the Prophets 130. 2 Jan 1839, Luke 4:18, The Preacher of the Gospel "Very well suited for the poorer class--or, in perilous or apprehensive times" 131. 5 Jan 1839, Rev. 22:12, The judge of the Quick and the Dead (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 132 & 133. 29 Mar 1840, Luke 13:5, On the Nature of repentance, and the only true method of atttaining it. 29 Mar 1840, Luke 13:5 134. 5 Jul 1840, Phil. 4:19, Man's needs supplied from God's Riches 135. 12 Apr 1840, Luke 22:19 136. [c. 1840] Isa. 48:18 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - 137. N.D., Matt. 18:35, The Cruel Servant 138. N.D., Isa. 48:18, The Divine Commandments Sources of Peace 139. N.D., Eccl. 12:7, The End of Man's Earthly History (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - 140. N.D., Psalm 37:37, Funeral 141 & 142. N.D., Psalm 40:8, Sins Remembered by God; N.D., Isa. 43:25, Sins Blotted Out by God 143. N.D., Luke 7:37-38, The Character of the Pardoned 144. N.D., Luke 10:41-42, True Religion Exemplified in Mary (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - 145. N.D., Psalm 131:2, Weanedness of Soul 146. N.D., Job 38:7 147. N.D., Matt. 9:2, Miracle of the Sick of the Palsy 148. N.D., 2 Kings 7:2, The Unbelief of the Samaritan Lord. And a fragment in John (II) Southcomb's hand, 1 p. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Edmund Southcomb (1792-1854)
    - 149. 10 Jul 1814, 1 John 2:17 150. 18 Dec 1818, John 5:40-42, The Reasons why men do not come to Christ. 151. [1819] or later, Luke 17:17-18 152. [1819] or later, Matt. 8:2 153. [1819] or later, Luke 17:12-13 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 154. [1819] or later, Hab. 2:14 155. 13 Feb 1820, 1 Kings 13:21, On indecision in Religion 156. 5 Mar 1820, Matt. 15:28, Second Sunday in Lent 157. 26 Mar 1820, 1 Peter 5:7, Casting Our Care upon God (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 158. 23 Dec 1820, 2 Cor. 4:17 159. 8 Jul 1821, Luke 15:10 160. 16 Sep 1821, 1 Cor. 10:11-12 161. 23 Sep 1821, 1 Cor. 15:9-10 162. 14 Oct 1821, Luke 18:14, From the Gospel of the Eleventh Sunday after Trinity (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 163. 26 Dec 1821, 1 John 4:8, God is Love 164. 28 Dec 1821, John 11:25-27 165. 30 Jun 1822, 1 Sam. 12:24-25, Fourth Sunday after Trinity 166. 27 Oct 1822, Isa. 64:6, A Sermon Occasioned by the Death of the Rev'd. J.B. Karstake (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 167. 28 Nov 1824, Rom. 13:12 168. [1828] or later, Psalm 30:1-2 169. [1829] or later, Matt. 6:11 170. Aug 1831, Luke 13:6-7 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 171. [1831] or later, Heb. 6:11, The "Fifth Month" Sermon 172. Sep 1832, Deu. 34:5, The Death of Moses 173. 1 Jan 1840, Gen. 1:14, For New Year's Day, or otherwise 174. c. 1843, 2 Kings 12:4-5, Society for enlarging, building and repairing Churches and Chapels (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 175. Oct 1847, Jer. 5:24 176. 16 Mar 1851, Mark 5:27-28, The Woman who touched Jesus was made Whole 177. N.D., 1 Cor. 11:26, On Errors Arising from a Misunderstanding of the Holy Sacrament of the Lord's Supper. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Anonymous and Unattributed
    Eleven sermons are in one hand; six are in other hands.
    - 178. 8 Oct 1826, Mark 1:41-43 179. 27 Jul 1828, Acts 8:36-37 180. 7 Nov 1830, Heb. 11:14-16 181. 3 Jul 1831, Isa. 1:2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 182. 24 Jul 1831, 2 Cor. 8:9 183. 24 Jul 1831, Matt. 7:21 184. 28 Aug 1831, 2 Cor. 3:18 185. 4 Sep 1831, Gal. 5:24 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 186. 16 Oct 1831, Matt. 22:5, 20th Sunday after Trinity 187. 29 Oct 1831, Hab. 2:4, 21st Sunday after Trinity 188. 18 Dec 1831, Isa. 52:7 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 189. [1834] or later,2 Cor. 9:9, On Beneficence (P. Picot) 190. 13 Aug 1837, Luke 18:36-38, On Bartimeus 191 & 192. 27 Aug 1843, 1 John 5:3, Two Sermons on the Precepts of Xianity not Grievous, Abp. Tillotson's Sermons Abridged by D. Henry 193. 2 Jan 1844, Matt. 18:14, Charity Sermon (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 194. 5 Jul 1857, 1 Cor. 3:8 195. N.D., unsigned, 'Skeletons," possibly extracts from work by John Harvey, 1714-1758 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - John Ladaveze Hamilton Southcomb (1817-1886)
    - 196. 14 Jul 1844, Josh. 18:5 197. 10 Nov 1844, Rom. 6:16 198. 24 Nov 1844, Jonah 4:4 199. 15 Dec 1844, Heb. 11:6 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 200. 16 Feb 1845, John 14:22-23 201. 23 Feb 1845, Matt. 13:58 202. 9 Mar 1845, John 8:51 203. 27 Apr 1845, John 16:23 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 204. 15 Jan 1845, Jam. 1:2-3 205. 17 Aug 1845, Matt. 26:41 206. 28 Dec 1845, John 15:4 207. 18 Mar 1846, Jam. 4:13-14 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 208. 22 Mar 1846, Mark 10:45 209. 28 Oct 1846, 2 Cor. 6:9 210. 15 Nov 1846, Matt. 13:30 211. 13 Dec 1846, John 6:53 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 212. 18 Apr 1847, Gen. 5:24, The Colonel Fulford's Death 213. 24 May 1847, Gen. 11:6-8 214. 26 Sep 1847, Jude 20-21 215. 2 Apr 1848, Heb. 4:15 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 216. 23 Jul 1848, Matt. 9:36-37, For the Propagation of the Gospel in Foreign Parts 217. 26 Nov 1848, John 6:6, For the End of the Ecclesiastical Year 218. 24 Dec 1848, John 4:1, Deference to Christian Authority 219. 14 Jan 1849, Rom. 12:6-8 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 220. 10 Apr 1849, Luke 24:36 221. 17 Jan 1849, Isa. 25:8, On the Death of Mr. W. Lavemer of Down Farm 222. 23 Sep 1849, Psalm 65:11, Harvest Sermon 223. 26 Sep 1849, Psalm 25:6-7, Day of Humiliation for Cholera (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 224. 21 Oct 1849, Matt. 9:2 225. 28 Oct 1849, Luke 14:23 226. 18 Nov 1849, 2 Tim. 1:7 227. 25 Nov 1849, Heb. 1:10-12 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 228. 30 Nov 1849, Rom. 10:9-10, St. Andrew's Day 229. 9 Dec 1849, Isa. 5:1-2 230. 26 Dec 1849, Acts 7:55, St. Stephen's Day 231. 13 Jan 1850, Luke 2:49, Gospel for the 1st after Epiphany (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 232. 20 Jan 1850, John 2:10, From the Gospel for 2nd After Epiphany 233. 2 Feb 1850, Luke 2:22, Purification of B.V.M. 234. 3 Feb 1850, Gen. 6:5, Sexagesima 235. 10 Feb 1850, 1 Cor. 13:13, Quinquagesima (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 236. 17 Feb 1850, Matt. 4:11, 1st Sunday in Lent 237. 24 Feb 1850, Luke 7:23 238. 17 Mar 1850, Gal. 4:28-29 239. 29 Mar 1850, Pet. 2:24, Good Friday (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 240. 26 Mar 1850, Matt. 3:16-17, Trinity Sunday 241. 16 Jun 1850, Eze. 34:5, For National Sunday 242. 15 Sep 1850, 1 Kings 8:63, Dedication of Churches 243. 22 Sep 1850, Rom. 9:17 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 244. 27 Oct 1850, Matt. 18:14 245. 29 Dec 1850, Psalm 90:12, For the End of the Year 1850 246. 1 May 1851, John 14:8, Ss. Philip & James 247. 24 Aug 1851, Luke 10:41-41 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 248. 31 Aug 1851, Matt. 8:11-12 249. 14 Sep 1851, 2 Kings 23:1-2, Fair Sunday 250. 30 Nov 1851, Matt. 6:10, For Jubilee of S.P.G.F.P. 251. 21 Dec 1851, Matt. 6:20, Funeral (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 252. 25 Dec 1851, John 1:14, Christmas 253. 28 Dec 1851, Pet. 3:14, End of the Year 254. 25 Feb 1852, Psalm 69:10 255. 29 Feb 1852, Matt. 4:4, First Sunday in Lent (Box 6, Folder 15)